（物种起源 作者）
（查尔斯·达尔文 文学硕士）
（缅因号战舰因不明生物 引起爆炸事故）
（声纳系统发现不明物体）
（灾难）
（失踪潜艇最后现身处）
（政府否认第三起失踪事件）
（比基尼岛）
（帝王计划）
（阿尔贡国立实验室）
（辐射区域）
（帝王怪兽）
（帝王计划）
（高危爆炸物）
十
Ten...
九 八
...nine, eight...
七 六
...seven, six...
五 四
...five, four...
三 二
...three, two...
一
...one.
《哥斯拉》
(1999年 菲律宾）
（环球西部矿业）
是芹泽博士吗
Dr. Serizawa?
我是杰瑞·博伊德 我来提醒你
Jerry Boyd. I'm warning you, it's a mess.
情况非常糟糕
It's just a total mess.
今早我奉命来查看情况
Monarch sent me in this morning.
我告诉他们 我们需要你
Took a look around, but I told them we needed you.
上个月矿工们发现了放射性矿囊
They picked up a radiation pocket out here last month.
他们很激动 以为找到了铀矿床
They got excited, thinking they had a uranium deposit.
开始往这里调集大型机械
They started stacking up the heavy machinery and then...
可是 谷底…
Well, the valley floor...
突然发生塌陷
...collapsed into a cavern below.
掉进了地下洞穴 全都没了 都不见了
Just dropped away. Just gone.
初步统计有四十名矿工被埋在下面
Best guess right now is about 40 miners went down with it.
要进去吗
This way.
他们这儿刚发现放射性矿囊的时候
When they first discovered this pocket,
辐射强度只有现在的一半
the radiation levels were only half as strong.
好像是一接触到外面的空气
It's almost as if contact with the outside air...
就加速了某种反应的进程
...started catalyzing something.
这是某种化石 对吗
Some kind of fossils, right?
我挖矿三十多年了 从没见过这样的东西
I've been digging holes for 30 years, I've never seen anything like it.
我的上帝 这怎么可能
Oh, my God. Is it possible?
会是它吗
Is it him?
不
No.
这儿比它可老多了
This is much older.
我的天呐 伙计们 快来看看这个
Hey, guys. You gotta see this.
这是什么
What is it?
某种蛋吗
Some kind of egg?
休眠中的孢子
A dormant spore?
骨骼已经变成了化石
The bones are fossilized...
这个却没有 这个构造被完整地保留下来
...but this formation seems to be perfectly preserved.
这个看上去破了
This one looks broken.
好像有东西…
It's like something...
出来过
...came out of it.
（日本 雀路罗镇）
我来接 可能是找我的
I'll get it. It's probably for me.
（生日快乐）
你好
不 明石先生
No, Takashi.
不 明石先生 你先听我说
No. Takashi, just listen to me for a second.
我请求面谈 因为我必须关闭核反应堆
I'm asking for the meeting because if I have to shut the reactor down...
我不希望 你在事后才知道
...you're not gonna want to read about it in a memo.
我从菲律宾开始 就一直在跟踪研究这些震动
I've been following these tremors since they started in the Philippines...
现在都震到家门口了
...and now they're in our own backyard.
不 隼人说…
No, no, no. Hayato says...
我需要先跟你沟通一下
...I need to go through you about this.
听着 我在努力
Look, I'm just...
遵守公司规章制度 没别的意思 这是我的工作
...trying to follow the protocols set forth by the company. That's all. It's my job.
他醒了
He's awake.
我知道 他早就醒了
Oh, I know. He got up early.
我们怎么做
What are we gonna do?
穿好衣服 我来想办法
Get dressed. I'll figure it out.
- 好吗 - 好吧
- Okay? - Okay
再见 爸爸
Later, Dad.
明石先生 我很尊重你
With all due respect, Takashi, and honor...
敬佩你 发自内心地敬重你
...respect and honor, with all of that...
可作为工程师 我不能容忍在我负责的范围内
...I'm an engineer. I don't like unexplained frequency patterning...
存在无法解释的波段结构 我需要当面谈请你理解
...near a plant where I'm responsible. I need a meeting. Make it happen.
妈妈再见
Bye. Mom!
他给你做了个徽章
He made you a sign.
- 什么 - 你的生日徽章
- What? - Your birthday sign.
- 他花了很多心思 - 上帝啊
- He worked so hard. - Oh, God.
我今天早点儿回家
I'm gonna come home early.
先开车去接他
I'll take the car and pick him up...
然后去买生日蛋糕 怎么样
...and we can get a proper cake. Okay?
听着 我要知道…
Listen, I need to know...
这不是传感器的问题 懂吗
...that it's not the sensors. Okay?
我不能在会议上表现的像个美国疯子
I can't be calling this meeting and look like the American maniac.
所以到那后
So when we get there...
先别着急上楼 带人去地下五层看看
...don't even bother coming up. Just grab a team and go down to Level 5.
你不是疯子
You're not a maniac.
我是说 你在这个问题上没疯
I mean, you are, just not about this.
我们肯定是忽视了什么
Must be something we're not thinking of.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
什么 难道…
What? Is it...
- 对 没错 - 我都忘了
- Yes, it is. Ha, ha. - Oh, I forgot all about it.
- 生日快乐 - 谢谢
- Happy birthday. - Thank you.
最好天天过生日
I should have a birthday more often. Ha, ha.
- 这是什么 - 地震波异常
- What is this? - Seismic anomaly.
时间单位是分钟
This graph is minutes.
X轴是分钟不是天数 这是刚出来的
X is minutes, not days. This is now.
等等 地震波异常
Wait, hold on. Seismic activity?
你的意思是说 这是地震的前兆
Seismic? You're talking about earthquakes?
不 地震波是杂乱的 锯齿状
No, earthquakes are random, jagged.
这个是有规律的 在增强
This is consistent, increasing.
波形很明显
This is a pattern.
为了安全措施
今日将召开紧急安全会议
都好了 我们动作快点
All right. Let's make this quick.
会上将对安全措施进行详细说明
位置在第一休息室
时间是…
明石 到底是怎么回事 这个你看了吗
Takashi. What the hell is going on? Have you seen this?
看了 现在不是…
Yeah. Maybe not such...
开会的时候
...good time for a meeting.
震源是什么
What's the source?
震中在哪里
Where's the epicenter?
还不知道 但是一直在持续地增强
We don't know. But it keeps getting stronger.
肯定能找到中心点
It's gotta be centered somewhere.
隼人
Hayato.
没有人汇报过
No one else is reporting it.
我们正在跟中州
We are contacting every other plant in the Kanto region.
东海和富士山所有的核电站联络
Tokai, Fujiyama.
他们没受影响
They're unaffected.
不过 我认为我们监测到的应该是 菲律宾地震的余震
But my guess is these readings are just aftershocks from the Philippine earthquake.
是在超负荷工作吗
Are we at full function?
是的 没错
Yes, we are.
为了安全起见 应该下调能量值
But perhaps we should be drawing down, to be safe.
必须马上关闭
Take us offline.
- 不 乔 我们应该快点儿… - 彻底关闭
- Now, Joe... - Do it!
马上动手 关闭反应堆
Now. Wind it down.
桑德拉
Sandra.
你在吗
Sandra, are you there?
我们回去
We're turning back.
都快点儿
Let's go.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
乔 你在吗
Joe, are you there?
要发生泄漏了 我们要回到封闭舱去
Joe, there's been a breach. We're heading back to the containment seal.
桑德拉 听我说 你们马上离开那儿
Listen. You need to get out of there.
快跑 如果核泄漏 即使穿着隔离服
If there's been a reactor breach, you won't last five minutes...
你们也活不过五分钟
...with or without the suits.
听见了吗
Do you hear me?
我听见了 我们来了
I hear you. We're coming!
我下去迎他们
I'll meet them there myself.
把安全门调成手动控制
Put the safety doors on manual override.
我不能那么干
I cannot do that!
先别关门 我妻子还在里面
Keep the doors open. My wife is still in there!
快
Come on...
大家 快点儿
...let's go!
明石 启动…
Tell me this door's...
手动控制了吗
...on manual.
手动 是的 但是乔 已经开始泄漏了
Yeah. But we are starting to breach!
我在这儿 他们到达后我来关闭
I'm here. Soon as they're through, I'll seal it.
桑德拉 亲爱的
Sandra, can you...
能听见吗 我在门这里
...hear me? I'm at the door.
桑德拉
Sandra?
桑德拉 我在等你
Sandra, I'm waiting for you.
我在安全门这里
I'm at the checkpoint.
你得快跑 亲爱的 越快越好
But you have to run as fast as you can.
我知道
I am!
铃木
Kenji. Kenji...
我们得快走
...we need to go!
乔 关闭安全门
明石 他们还没进来
封闭通道
Close the door!
否则整座城都会被炸毁的
Seal the corridor or the whole city will be exposed.
桑德拉
Sandra?
- 乔 能听见吗 - 是的
- Joe? Joe, can you hear me? - Yes.
- 你在吗 - 桑德拉 我在 你能听见吗
- Are you there? - Sandra, I'm here. Can you hear me?
是的
Yeah.
乔 太晚了 我们回不去了
Joe, it's too late. We're not coming.
别这么说 不要这么说
No, don't say that! Don't you say that!
你们快跑 我等你们
Run as hard as you can, honey.
乔 你必须关上安全门
Joe, you have to close the door.
你要为我们的儿子活下去
You have to live for our son.
- 乔 封死门 快 - 上帝
- Joe, seal the door! Now! - Oh, my God.
五秒 四秒
Five seconds! Four seconds!
对不起
I'm sorry.
照顾好福特
Take care of Ford.
做个好爸爸
Be a good father.
我会的
I Will.
告诉他 我爱他
We didn't make it.
紧急情况 大家快出去
Let's go out!
快点 福特 快跑
Hurry! Come on! Ford!
(15年后）
起立
On your feet!
有家人在等你吗
You got family waiting for you?
但愿吧
I hope so.
你离家多久了
How long you been away?
十四个月
Fourteen months.
慢慢来吧
Take it slow.
就当是一个新的挑战
It's the one thing they don't train you for.
好了 我们走
All right! Let's go!
- 就不告诉你 - 我能看看吗
- I can't tell you. - Can I see it?
别让他看
Don't let him see.
我的天呐
Whoa. Oh, my God.
- 欢迎你回家 - 天呐 快看
- It's a welcome home cake. - Look at that.
那个是你
That's you.
- 另外那个是我 - 写的是什么
- And that's me. - What's it say?
欢迎爸爸回家
"Welcome home, Daddy."
爸爸回家
Daddy's home.
- 爸爸回家 - 每晚都有蛋糕
- Daddy's home. - Cake every night.
- 是啊 看把你美的 - 爸爸回家…
- Yeah, that's not happening. - Daddy's home equals...
等于每晚都有蛋糕
...cake every night.
你怎么把巧克力吃到眼睛上了
How did you manage to get chocolate on your eyeball?
是爸爸弄的
Daddy did it.
你再闹我可就…
I can't sleep with you...
不跟你一块睡了
...making all this noise.
来 盖好被子
Come on, let's get you into bed.
睡吧 大个子
Okay, big man.
要服从命令
Time to hit the rack.
爸爸
Dad?
什么事
Yeah?
你明天还会在这儿吗
Are you still gonna be here tomorrow?
当然
Yeah.
好了 快睡觉吧
Come on, let's get some sleep.
转过来 就这么脸对脸 别紧张
Turns around, nose-to-nose, he says, "At ease, lieutenant."
我天天在想你
God, I missed your laugh.
我也想你
I missed you.
我得接一下 别是医院的
I should get that. No, it could be work.
- 我接一下 - 你不必的 快点
- I need to get that. - You don't need to. Come on.
你好
Hello?
对 没错 我是布罗迪太太
Yeah, this is Mrs. Brody.
告诉他 你正忙着满足丈夫的需要呢
Tell him you're busy tending to your husband's needs.
对 他是我丈夫
Yeah, he's my husband.
告诉他 我们什么都不想买
Tell them we're not gonna buy it.
好的 先生 你能等一下吗
Yes, sir. Could you just hold on one moment?
领事馆打来的
It's the consulate.
乔在日本被逮捕了
Joe's been arrested in Japan.
艾丽 我的裤子在哪儿
Elle, I can't find my pants.
在那个抽屉里
They're in the other drawer.
他为什么会擅闯隔离区
So why was he trespassing in the quarantine zone?
还能为什么
Ugh. Why do you think?
寻找真相的孤胆英雄
The lone crusader for the truth.
没法理解他那些疯狂的理论
All his crackpot cuckoo theories.
你父亲是个好人 他现在需要你的帮助
Your father is a good man. He just needs your help right now.
福特 他已经什么都没有了
Ford, he's lost everything.
对 我也一样 但我至少挺过来了
Yeah, so did I. But you know what? I got over it.
是啊 看得出来
Right. I can see that.
对不起 只是…
I'm sorry. It's just...
每次我跟他亲近 他就想把我拉回到过去
Every time I let him in close, he always tries to drag me back.
我做不到 我不能让我的家人再受伤害
And I can't. I can't put our family through that.
可他也是你的家人
Well, he is your family.
过来
Hey. Come here.
你只不过就离开几天而已 对吗
You know you're only gonna be gone for a few days, right?
然后就会回到我身边
And then you are gonna come back to me.
对
Yeah. Yeah.
又不是世界末日
It's not the end of the world.
（东京）
- 爸爸 - 光司 你这个混蛋
你干什么别问了 快走
你再这样会无可救药的
我明白
我这不常有人来
I don't get many visitors.
看出来了
Clearly.
你就睡这儿
This is you here.
即使是博士
Even, uh, Ph.D.'s...
做英语外教也赚不了多少钱
...don't get much teaching English as a second language.
（核危机持续恶化）
收拾好了
Here we go.
这毛巾是干净的
And a towel.
（熔毁 雀路罗电子公司欲盖弥彰）
好吧
All right.
那么…
So...
炸弹生意怎么样
...how's the bomb business?
这年头儿这生意肯定红火
It must be a growth area these days.
我的工作叫做爆炸物处理
It's called "explosive ordnance disposal."
(1954年南太平洋的隐秘事件）
我们不是投掷炸弹
My job isn't dropping bombs.
而是阻止
It's stopping them.
（隔离区 雀路罗镇周围戒备森严）
爸爸
Dad.
艾丽还好吧
...how's Elle doing?
还有萨姆 我的天呐
And Sam. Oh, my God. He must be...
他现在多大了 三岁还是三岁半
...what? Three? Three and a half?
快五岁了
He's almost 5.
还以为你已经想通了 回波定位法
I thought you were over this. "Echolocation"?
种群间的沟通
"Parasitic communication..."
不好意思 别动这些 弄乱了我就找不到了
Please don't, if you don't mind. I have everything the way I like it.
我正在学习生物声学
I'm just... I'm studying bioacoustics.
你回到那地方去干什么
What were you doing, going back there?
- 所谓非法入侵根本就是胡说八道 - 你犯了法
- This trespassing stuff, that was bull. - You broke the law.
我只是想回我们以前住的房子
I was trying to get back to our old house.
- 可房子在隔离区 - 对 没错
- In a quarantine zone. - Precisely.
新的数据跟那天一模一样
The new readings are exactly like they were on that day...
我可以证明给你看
...and I can prove it to you.
如果够走运
With a little luck, if I can get back...
让我回到那房子
...to the house...
我可以给全世界证明这不是自然灾害 不是地震波异常
...I can show you and the world this was not from a natural disaster. This was...
爸爸
Dad!
你妈妈留在了那里 福特
Your mom's out there, Ford.
对我来说…
To me...
她一直在那里
...she'll always be there.
当初撤离的太仓促
They evacuated us so quickly.
甚至连她的照片都没留下
I don't even have a picture of her.
你不能再这样了
This has to stop.
你知道我已经尽力了
You know I did everything I could.
你知道 对吗
You know that, right?
跟我回家吧
Let me take you home.
我们一起回家
Come home with me.
家里有个男孩在盼着他的爷爷
I got a little boy who's desperate to see his grandpa.
我们明天就动身
We can leave tomorrow.
先生 大致情况就是这样
好的 非常感谢
具体的细节 还是见面再说吧
那好吧 我尽快赶到那里
如果你要过来 最好快点儿 再见
好的 再见 非常感谢
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我得再去那儿一次 福特
I'm heading back out there, Ford.
- 不行 我不同意你去 - 一个小时就能回来
- No. I don't think so. - One hour, in and out.
我必须去
I have to go!
我回到这里 花了六年的时间
I came back here and wasted six years...
望着那片铁丝网
...staring through that barbed wire, thinking it was...
那可能是场军事事故或者是因为设计上
...a military mistake or some horrible design flaw
有大失误所以他们要掩盖真相
they were covering up.
有一天
One day...
我遇见个在近海跑船运的人
...I met a guy who runs a cargo boat offshore.
（声学专家声称揭穿"奇怪的噪音"之谜）
他每天都会经过反应堆那里
Every day he goes right past the reactor site.
我让他替我在浮标上放置了频率监测器
So he places a couple frequency monitors on buoys for me.
两周前
Two weeks ago...
每隔一天我都会检查 反正闲着也是闲着
I check this thing like every other day just for the kick.
两周前 调节频率时
Two weeks ago, I'm tuning in...
我的天呐
...and, oh, my God...
收到了
...there it is.
不管到底是什么 它就在那儿
Whatever "it" is that's in there.
就是他们小心翼翼把守着的东西
Whatever it is they're guarding so carefully...
这东西又说话了
...started talking again.
我听见它在说话
And I mean talking.
我必须回到
I have to go back...
我们的房子
...to our house.
去找回我的磁盘 如果还在的话
I need my old disks, if they're still there.
里面的数据 跟这次的数据对比就能证明
I need the data to be able to prove a baseline here...
我的观点不是凭空妄想 我不是你想的那样
...that this isn't a fantasy, that I'm not what you think I am.
我会找到真相
I'm gonna find the truth...
了断这一切
...and end this.
无论代价是什么
Whatever it takes.
为什么你就不肯罢手
Why can't you just let it rest?
是我让你妈妈下去的
Because I sent her down there, son.
事故的原因没那么简单
This wasn't just a reactor meltdown.
我不想再听了
I don't wanna hear this.
我知道 知道你不想听
I know. I know you don't.
但你不能永远回避问题
But you can't keep running away.
不能把这一切跟过去一起埋葬
And, son, you can't bury this in the past.
（隔离区）
它们在怕什么
What spooked them?
爸爸 快点走吧 还有两个街区
Dad, come on. Let's go. It's only another two blocks.
爸爸
Dad!
我们还去不去了
Are we going home, or what?
你在干什么
Whoa! Hey, what are you doing?
爸爸
Dad?
很干净
It's clean.
我就知道
I knew it.
这儿的辐射指数本该是致命的 但却什么都没有
The radiation in this place should be lethal, but there's nothing.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
（生日快乐）
他们是要重建核电站
Are they rebuilding the plant?
不知道 我没看见
I don't know. I haven't seen...
五号车抓到入侵者 请求带往本部
你们在干什么 不许动 你们知道后果吗
出发
（雀路罗）
抓到入侵者
停
- 我们前往第四栋 - 好的 通行
十秒
Ten seconds. Ten seconds.
准备放水 拜托了 快点呼叫增援
加大压力 红色小组请进入警戒状态
七点二秒 越来越强烈
Seven-point-two seconds and getting stronger.
以指数趋势增涨
We're trending exponentially.
这是新高
That's our new curve.
上帝 比想象的还糟
Jesus, it's worse than we thought.
抱歉 芹泽博士
Excuse me, Dr. Serizawa?
刚刚抓到两名入侵者
Two men were just arrested in the Q-zone.
我们这儿有更重要的事情 让格雷厄姆博士处理吧
We've got bigger problems here. Have Dr. Graham take a look.
她在处理 她让我通知你们
She did, sir. She sent me.
有个人说他以前在这里工作过
One of them says he used to work here, doctor.
你不要再撒谎了
You are not fooling anybody...
十五年前 你跟大家说这是自然灾害
...when you say that what happened 15 years ago...
在他包里发现了这些磁盘和资料
Found these disks in his bag.
那不是地震
...was a natural disaster.
不知道该怎么处理
Not sure what to make of them.
也不是台风 不是吗
Not an earthquake, it wasn't a typhoon. Okay? So stop...
别费劲了 我懒得再跟你浪费口舌
Look, I'm tired of talking to you about this.
我要见我儿子
I want my son.
我要见我儿子 确保他没事
I wanna see my son. I wanna know that he's all right.
这家伙知道
This guy, this guy knows.
我儿子在哪儿
He knows where he is.
我要见我儿子
I want my son.
把我的包和磁盘还给我
And I want my bag and disks.
我要跟这里的负责人说话 不是你 不 不跟你说
And I wanna talk to somebody in charge, not you. No, not you.
不想跟你废话
I'm done talking to you.
行了吗 我知道你们正在看着我
All right? You're looking at me right now,
就像我在水族箱里一样 对吗
like I'm in a fish tank, right?
无所谓 因为我知道这里发生过什么
Fine. Because I know what happened here.
你们一直对外声称
And you keep telling everybody that this place...
这里是死亡地带 但事实不是这样
...is a death zone, but it's not.
你们撒谎
You're lying.
因为事情的真相是
Because what's really happening...
你们在这里藏匿了什么东西
...is that you're hiding something out there.
我说对了 不是吗
I'm right, aren't I?
我妻子就死在这儿
My wife died here!
她是被杀死在这儿的
Something killed my wife.
我有权…
And I have...
知道
...a right to know!
我有权知道真相
I deserve answers!
这些磁盘和资料…
All these items...
我检查过了
...they were found on him.
- 日期是十五年前的 - 我以为那天…
- And the date. Look, 15 years ago. - I thought all of the data...
所有的数据都已经被毁了
...from that day was lost.
看来不是
I guess not.
看啊
You see?
又出现了
You see? There it is again.
这可不是变压器发生故障
That is not a transformer malfunction.
这绝对是一种电磁脉冲
That is an electromagnetic pulse.
好几英里之内一切电器…
It affects everything electrical...
都会受到影响
...for miles and miles...
现在又发生了
...and it is happening again.
这也是最初发生事故的原因
This is what caused everything in the first place.
你们还不明白吗
Don't you see that?
这会把我们直接送回石器时代
And it is gonna send us back to the Stone Age.
我们就要大难临头了
You have no idea what's coming.
脉冲几秒钟一次
Pulses are seconds apart.
越来越强 会影响到电网
They're getting stronger. It's affecting the power grid.
有辐射泄漏迹象吗
Any radiation leakage?
伽玛读数仍然为零
Gamma levels are still zero.
把三个反应堆都吸干了
It sucked all three reactors dry.
退后
它结束进食了
It's done feeding.
这是什么
What's this?
- 上帝 同样的波形 - 十五年前…
- It's the same pattern. - Fifteen years ago...
- 它就是罪魁祸首 - 电磁脉冲…
- ...it's what caused the meltdown. - An electromagnetic...
是个手段 它在吸收能量 吸光所有辐射
...pulse. That's what it's building to. Converting all that radiation...
直到破茧而出
...until it hatches.
不能再继续了
We have to shut down.
撤出第一区
Secure the grid.
启动紧急预案
Wildfire protocols.
所有人员 立即撤出第一区 马上
All personnel, clear the first perimeter immediately!
这不是演习 请无关人员 所有人员请立即前往避难所
抓到的入侵者如何处置
怎么了你去哪儿
What's going on? Hey, where you going?
已经就绪
Grid's secure.
动手吧
Kill it.
波形成直线了
All readings are flatlined.
派人看看
Get a visual.
天呐 电网被电磁脉冲攻击 电全断了
Jesus. Check the grid. Hit us with an EMP. We're losing power!
- 启动备用发电机 - 已经启动
- Get the backup generators online. - Working on it.
但是脉冲线路瘫痪
That pulse fried every circuit.
- 检查线路 - 再试备用发电机
- Check the cage. - Trying the backup generators.
好了
Here we go.
大家快出去
Everybody out!
快
Now!
放我出去
Hey! Let me out! Hey!
不 等等
No! No, wait!
停下
Stop!
福特
Ford!
爸爸
Dad!
这是以前从没经历过的
It was unlike anything I've ever experienced before.
对 是福特·布罗迪
Yeah, it's, uh, Ford Brody.
从日本飞往旧金山
Japan to San Francisco.
好 我能不能 给您留下我的手机号码…
Okay, could I at least... if you could let me leave you my cell...
你好
Hello?
该死的
Damn it!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事的
Hey, it's okay.
爸爸不会有事的
It's okay. Daddy's gonna be okay.
不会有事的
Daddy's gonna be okay.
这个区域现在由军队接管
This area is now under Naval military jurisdiction.
如有疑问…
All personnel must report...
请与当值军官联系
...to the duty officer for debriefing.
芹泽博士
Dr. Serizawa!
Dr. Serizawa.
我是罗素·汉普顿
Captain Russell Hampton.
很高兴能找到你
Glad to find you. I've been briefed...
我对您正在参与的帝王计划有所了解
...on your work with Operation Monarch.
我被告知您的机构对不明生物的研究
Now, I'm told your organization has situational awareness...
已经有了突破性的进展
...of our unidentified creature?
是这样吗
Is that right?
我是来通知你 帝王计划…
We are now taking over operational authority...
现在已经被我们军方接管了
...from Monarch. So I'm gonna need you...
所以请您跟我走一趟
...to come with me.
你需要什么人协助你吗
Is there any other personnel you need?
没事的爸爸
They'll take care of you.
我会一直陪着你
I'll be right next to you.
好的
Okay.
那两个
Them.
好了 检查他的生命体征
Let's get his vitals.
- 爸爸 - 脉搏很微弱 心率每分钟125
- Dad. Dad. - Radial pulse is weak. I'm counting 125.
没事的
It's okay.
你是对的
You were right.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
回到家人身边
Go home to your family.
保证他们的安全
You keep them safe.
- 好吗 - 好的
- Okay? - Okay.
无论发生什么
Whatever it takes.
保护他们
Whatever it ta...
爸爸别睡
Hey, stay with me.
爸爸
Dad?
- 爸爸 - 脉搏在变弱 快感觉不到了
- Dad? - Radial pulse is weaker. Barely feel it.
他要不行了
We're losing him.
- 乔 能听见吗 - 开始房颤了
- Joe, can you hear me? - He's going into A-fib.
再来一千毫克肾上腺素 四十个单位的加压素
Give me another epi, one milligram, and 40 units of vasopressin.
千万别睡 坚持住 乔 加油伙计
Stay with us. Come on, Joe. Hang in there, buddy.
（美国海军萨拉托加号航母 日本海岸线）
这简直就是在大海捞针
This is our needle in a haystack, people.
穆托
MUTO.
未明种类的巨型陆生生物
Massive unidentified terrestrial organism.
但是现在不再是陆生了 它会飞了
It is, however, no longer terrestrial. It is airborne.
现在全世界都以为这是一场地震
The world still thinks this was an earthquake...
那我们最好的办法就是保持现状
...and it would be preferable that that remain so.
(六点三级地震波及日本东部）
消失之前 它穿过太平洋往东面去了
Before we lost sight, it was headed east across the Pacific...
并发射出破坏力很强的电磁脉冲波
...and had emitted enough EMP disruption...
我们的雷达和卫星传送系统
...to create havoc with our radar and satellite feeds...
都受到了严重的干扰 暂时只有视频可以追踪到
...and reduce us, for the moment, to a strictly visual pursuit.
我特别强调暂时
I emphasize "for the moment"...
是因为我们很快会恢复
...because we will get on our game...
一定会找到这东西
...and we will find this thing.
这也是我们的职责所在
It is imperative that we do so.
请把所有的搜寻方案
Captain, I want any...
- 尽快报上来 - 是 长官
- ...and all search options on this table ASAP. - Yes, sir.
芹泽博士
Dr. Serizawa.
我是威廉·姆斯坦兹海军上将
Admiral William Stenz.
- 很高兴认识您 - 欢迎加入我们
- Nice to meet you. - Glad to have you on board.
老师
Sensei.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 尽管死亡人数仍在增加… - 他死了
- Authorities issued a statement... - Brody's dead.
当局发布了一份声明称…
...claiming the nuclear contamination...
核污染并没有扩散
...is at no risk of spreading, even as the death toll rises.
布罗迪中尉
Lieutenant Brody?
芹泽博士
Dr. Serizawa.
请您节哀
My condolences.
您父亲的事我们很遗憾
We are deeply sorry for your loss, lieutenant.
但我们需要您的帮助
But I'm afraid we need your help.
这是美国海军鹦鹉螺号
This is the USS Nautilus.
1954年
In 1954...
一艘核潜艇首次抵达前所未有的深度
...the first time a nuclear submarine ever reached the lower depths...
惊醒了某种生物
...it awakened something.
美国人最先以为是俄国人干的
The Americans first thought that it was the Russians.
俄国人却以为是美国人
The Russians thought that it was them.
那些五十年代进行的核弹试验
All those nuclear bomb tests in the '50s...
不是试验
Not tests.
他们是想杀了这东西
They were trying to kill it.
就是它
Him.
- 一个远古的掠食者之王 - 比人类…
- An ancient alpha predator. - Millions of years...
还早几百万年
...older than mankind.
当时地球上的放射性
From an age when the Earth...
比现在强烈十倍
...was 10 times more radioactive than today.
这只生物和它的同伴们
This animal and others like it...
将放射物当成食品来使用
...consumed this radiation as a food source.
随着地表的放射程度减弱
As the levels on the surface naturally subsided...
逐渐适应了生活在海洋深处
...these creatures adapted to live deeper in the oceans.
地下更深处
Further underground.
从星球的核心处获取放射物质
Absorbing radiation from the planet's core.
我们为之工作的机构 帝王
The organization we work for, Monarch, was established...
就是因为这个发现而建立的
...in the wake of this discovery.
一个秘密成立的
A multinational coalition...
多国联合机构
...formed in secrecy...
去搜寻它
...to search for him.
研究它
Study him.
竭尽所能了解它
Learn everything we could.
我们管它叫
We call him...
哥斯拉
...Gojira.
原始生态系统的
The top of...
最高统治者
...a primordial ecosystem.
它是神 无论从什么角度看
A god, for all intents and purposes.
- 一只兽 - 十五年前…
- A monster. - Fifteen years ago...
我们在菲律宾 发现了另一头巨型动物的化石
...we found a fossil of another giant animal in the Philippines.
很像哥斯拉 但它…
Like Gojira. But this creature...
很久以前就死了
...died long ago.
被它们杀死的
Killed by these.
这是寄生孢子
Parasitic spores.
一个母体 其余是孵化的 一家矿产公司无意中…
One dormant. But the other hatched. Catalyzed when a mining company...
挖到它们的巢穴
...unknowingly drilled into its tomb.
孵化洞穴直指距离最近的放射源所在
The hatchling burrowed straight for the nearest source of radiation...
你父亲所在的雀路罗核电站
...your father's power plant in Janjira...
并在其中孵化了十五年 利用那里的放射性燃料
...and cocooned there for 15 years, absorbing its radioactive fuel...
- 孕育 成长 - 直到今天
- ...to gestate, to grow. - Until it hatched...
像蝴蝶一样孵化成你看到的东西
...like a butterfly into the creature you saw today.
等等 你早就知道这些
Wait. You knew about this?
这个东西 一直都知道 为什么有机会的时候…
This thing? The whole time? Why didn't you...
- 没杀了它 - 它一直从反应堆里
- ...kill it when you had the chance? - It was absorbing...
吸收放射性物质
...radiation from the reactors.
我们担心杀掉它…
We worried killing it...
会释放出辐射 造成严重的后果
...might release that radiation and endanger millions.
所以 我们的任务是控制它
That's why our mission was to contain it.
研究它的生物性 了解它
To study its biology, to understand it.
我们知道这只生物 对它一定范围内的一切
We knew the creature was having an electrical effect...
都具有电场效应
...on everything within a close proximity.
但不知道的是
What we didn't know...
它在电磁脉冲袭击方面
...was that it could harness this same power...
具有同样的能力
...in an EMP attack.
但你父亲知道
But your father did.
他预测到了
He predicted it.
他还说过什么话
What else did he say?
请好好想想 布罗迪先生
Please try to remember, Mr. Brody.
任何话可能都有用 仔细想一想
Anything that would help us. Anything at all.
我没太在意
I didn't listen.
我觉得他是疯了
I just thought he was crazy.
他沉迷于这些东西
He was obsessed with all this...
什么关于动物的交流
Said something about an animal call.
什么东西在说话
Something talking.
说话
Talking?
他说他在研究着什么
He said he was studying something.
回波定位法
Echolocation.
如果那天穆托说过话
If the MUTO was talking that day...
你父亲肯定发现了什么东西在做回应
...your father must have discovered something talking back.
- 再查查 - 好的
- Check again. - Yup.
看是什么在回应
Search for a response call.
那东西
This parasite.
现在还在那儿蛰伏着 接下来呢
It's still out there. Where's it headed?
穆托很年轻
The MUTO is young...
在生长
...growing.
接下来它会寻找食物
It will be looking for food.
寻找放射源
Sources of radiation.
我们在监测所有已知地点
We're monitoring all known sites...
如果不能尽快找到
...but if we don't find it soon...
会怎么样
Then what?
大自然有种能力
Nature has an order.
一种重建平衡的能力
A power to restore balance.
我相信它就是那种能力
I believe he is that power.
先生 我们目前距离夏威夷五十英里
Sir, right now we're 50 miles from Hawaii.
这架飞机会带您过去
This transport will take you there.
会有一架商务机带您返回旧金山
You're catching a commercial flight back to San Francisco.
你该去刷牙了
I'm gonna need you to brush your teeth.
太糟糕了 嘴里好多细菌
Disgusting! Those are terrible!
再不刷就该臭了
We gotta brush them!
天然气和电力系统损毁严重 部分地区通讯中断
Citizens within a 100-mile radius...
该地区方圆一百英里范围内的居民已被疏散
...are being temporarily evacuated from the area.
我是艾丽 我现在不在 有事请留言
Hey, this is Elle. You missed me. Please leave a message.
艾丽
Elle.
我不知道他们在新闻上是怎么说的
I don't know what they're saying on the news.
在日本发生了一起事故
There was an accident in Japan.
爸爸去世了
Dad's gone.
等见了面再细说
I'll explain when I see you.
我现在去夏威夷 在那里搭机回去
I'm headed to Hawaii. I'm gonna catch a flight from there.
很快能见面
I'll see you soon.
继续往下
Keep scrolling.
靠近最后 在脉冲前面
Near the end. Before the EMP.
这儿
There.
有东西做出了回应
Something responded.
（夏威夷 檀香山）
乘客您好 欢迎乘坐列车
Aloha, and welcome aboard.
本次列车即将启动
The train will begin moving shortly.
为了他人着想请不要吸烟 谢谢
For the comfort of others, no smoking, please. Thank you.
为了您的安全请勿倚靠车门
Please remember to stay clear of the automatic doors.
昭夫 不可以
Akio!
妈妈
Mama!
喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey.
妈妈
Mama!
不要 请帮帮忙
我打不开门 小心 别担心 你们等在这里
I can't open it. Look, don't worry. Just wait there.
我会带他回来的
I'll bring him back.
好吗
Okay?
妈妈
Mama!
- 嗨 小孩 - 妈妈
- Whoa. Hey. Whoa, kid. - Mama!
我会带他回来
It's okay. I'm gonna bring him back.
好了 我会把你送回去的
All right. I'm gonna set you down there.
带你回去找爸爸妈妈
I'll get you back to your parents.
好吗
Okay?
给 是不是很喜欢这个
Here. Is this what you want?
帮我好好照顾他
Take good care of him for me.
但愿别耽误我赶飞机 孩子
I better not miss my flight, kid.
将军 我们收到一份情报
Admiral, received an intel report.
在距离夏威夷五十英里的海域 有一艘俄罗斯核潜艇失踪
We lost track of a nuclear Akula 50 nautical miles northwest of Hawaii.
可能是穆托干的
Could be the MUTO.
收到消息 俄罗斯潜艇在北太平洋失踪
Just got word of a missing Russian sub in the North Pacific.
马丁内兹
Martinez?
是 长官 特种部队斯巴达一号收到呼救信号
Aye. Special Forces Team Sparta 1 is picking up a distress signal...
在瓦胡岛 钻石头西北方向
...northwest of Diamond Head on the island of Oahu.
在地面向灯塔方向移动
They're on the ground, headed to the beacon.
距离上次讯号北北东五点二三
...on 5.23 north-northeast...
正步行前进
...of the last beacon. Moving in on foot.
谁能告诉我为什么要在丛林里…
Wanna tell me why we're looking...
寻找一艘俄罗斯潜艇吗
...for an Akula in the jungle?
没准是错了 俄罗斯人说
Probably a glitch. Russians said they...
在这里收到了信号
...got a ping from this location.
我收到信号了 就在正前方
Hey, I got a reading. It's right up ahead.
斯巴达一号 我是鹰眼
Sparta 1, this is Hawkeye.
我们收到了同样的信号 范围三十米
We're getting the same ping off the transponder. Range 30 meters.
看来你们接近了
Looks like you're getting warm.
这是什么
What the hell?
天呐
Jesus.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
三号守护人 我们找到了俄罗斯潜艇
Guardian 3, we located your Russian sub.
还有个不可思议的发现
You're not gonna believe what else we found.
上帝
Holy shit.
能看到潜艇在树木上方二三十米高
It appears to be rising approximately 20 to 30 meters...
看的很清楚
...above the tree line.
目测不出宽度
We can't tell how wide it is.
这秘密守不住了 别想着保密了
Cat's out of the bag, doctor. No more secrets.
现在最重要的就是安全
Our highest priority now is safety.
那岛上有将近一百万人
There's close to a million people on that island.
派人在空中盯着
Get me eyes in the air.
监测到不明物体 从太平洋方向逼近
We're picking up something else. Approaching from the Pacific.
马上查明到底是什么
We need to check out that object.
进入全面戒备
General quarters.
舰桥 我是舰长
Bridge, this is the captain.
- 你要去哪儿 - 去飞行甲板
- Where you going? - Up to the flight deck.
肯定是它来了
I think he is coming.
你想干什么
What are you doing?
我得去看一下
I have to see this.
呼叫二号 正在接近目标 准备行动
Two Charlie Six, we are circling the target. Go on your command.
我已经发现目标 十二点方向
Stand by, got a visual. Bogey at my 12.
小心 注意观察 随时准备开火
Be advised. Prepare to engage target.
三号守护人 我们这边
We're getting movement...
有动静
...down here.
注意隐蔽
Take cover!
控制中心 我失去了…
Control, I have...
动力 重复 我失去了…
...no power. I say again, I've lost all...
没事吧
You all right?
等十秒钟灯就会亮起来
You give it 10 seconds, lights gonna come back on.
别害怕
It's okay.
- 那是什么 - 你看见没有
- What was that? - Did you see that?
到底是什么
What is it?
爸爸
Dad!
佐伊
Zoe?
Zoe!
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
跑 快跑 是海啸 快跑
Run. Run! Tsunami! Tsunami!
亡命徒 目标出现在海岸
Target spotted offshore...
在你的方位以东两海里 可能是另一只怪物
...two knots due east of your position. Could be a second bogey.
有人受伤吗
Anybody hurt?
- 谁看见它往哪儿去了 - 没看见
- Anyone get an eyeball on the bogey? - Where is he?
怎么样
There you go.
我就说吧
What did I tell you?
谢谢
...please. Thank you.
蹲下
Get down!
快 快走
Let's go!
为了您的安全…
Remember to stay...
请勿倚靠车门
...clear of the doors.
快
Go, go, go!
发现目标 两点钟方向
Target in sight...
- 距离三百米 - 明白 我已经锁定目标
- ...two o'clock, 300 meters. - We're on 6-X-01. Target confirmed.
天呐
Jesus!
能告诉我们发生什么事了吗
Can you tell us what happened?
所有人都开始奔跑尖叫
... and everybody started running and screaming.
萨姆 把电视关了 行吗
Sam, please turn that TV off.
（檀香山几近毁灭）
听见我说话了吗
Hey, did you hear me?
关掉
Off.
（遇难檀香山… 萨拉托加号航空母舰部署）
好了萨姆 走吧
Come on, Sammy. Let's go.
该睡觉了
Let's go. It's bedtime.
- 萨姆 - 妈妈 看
- Sammy. - Mommy, look.
大恐龙
Dinosaurs.
请注意 新进病人…
Attention, please. Incoming patients...
- 请到… - 抱歉
- ...please proceed... - Excuse me.
抱歉 打扰一下
Hi. Excuse me. I'm sorry.
这孩子跟父母走散了
This boy's been separated from his parents.
先把这表填了
Fill this out. Be with you...
马上来帮你解决
...in just a minute.
你手机能打出去吗
Hey, you got service on that cell phone?
不行 连公用电话都打不了
No. The pay phones don't even work.
（登记处）
- 昭夫 - 昭夫
- Akio! - Akio!
妈妈 爸爸
Mama! Papa!
全体上车
Corporal, load up, load up.
中士 我是海军中尉布罗迪
Sergeant. Lieutenant Brody, U.S. Navy.
我需要你的帮助 我要去内陆
I need your help. I'm trying to get to the mainland.
今天算你走运 所有运输工具都往东面去
It's your lucky day. Everything not tied down is moving east.
- 它们往东跑了 - 对
- Whoa, is that where they're heading? - Yeah.
我们现在是专业打怪兽的
I guess we're monster hunters now.
卫星图像传送完毕
Satellite transfer complete.
模拟数据上传中
Simulations uploaded.
卫星追踪继续
Satellite tracking continues.
预计穆托会持续向东移动
Last satellite tracks predict the MUTO continuing due east.
综合所有数据 目标会在太平洋沿岸相遇
All our models have the targets converging on the Pacific Coast.
目前看 哥斯拉好像是在跟着它
As of now, it looks like Godzilla's still following the MUTO.
它在狩猎
He's hunting.
让所有船舰跟目标保持目前的距离
Have all vessels maintain current distance from target.
记录它们的速度和移动方向
And plot the speed and heading of these things.
我需要知道它们准确的登陆时间和方位
I wanna know exactly when and where they'll make landfall.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
博士 您刚才说的狩猎是什么意思
Doctor, what did you mean by "hunting"?
你觉得它是在追逐穆托吗
You think it's chasing this MUTO?
如果穆托是它的目标猎物
But if the MUTO is his prey...
这信号是在召唤
The signal shows a call.
- 它为什么自找麻烦 - 不 不是的
- Why call up a predator? - No, it didn't.
把哥斯拉招来…
I think Godzilla...
应该是个意外
...was only listening.
穆托肯定是在呼唤别的东西
The MUTO was calling something else.
那波形
The pattern.
注意搜寻内华达州
Focus the search on Nevada.
内华达 它怎么会去内华达
Nevada? Why would it go to Nevada?
- 这不可能 绝不可能 - 什么不可能
- It can't be. It's impossible. - What's impossible?
还有个完好无损的孢子体 在菲律宾矿场找到的
There was another spore, intact, found in the Philippine mine.
但是我们把它解剖了
But we vivisected it.
拿它做了好几年的实验
Ran every test on it for years.
是你亲自确认的 它是休眠的
You confirmed it for yourself. It was dormant!
也许现在不是了
Maybe not anymore.
这个孢子现在在哪儿 博士
This spore. Where is it now, doctor?
那东西辐射很大 被摧毁了
It was highly radioactive. It was disposed of.
被美国人拿走了
The Americans, they took it.
博士 它在哪儿
Doctor, where is it?
在你们存放核废料的地方
Where you put all your nuclear waste.
快
Go, go, go!
（尤卡山核废料存放处）
好了 开始吧
Right, let's go! Give me a Mark I...
每一间库房都要仔细检查
...eyeball on every vault.
安全
Clear!
- 安全 - 安全
- Clear! - Clear!
安全
Clear!
- 安全 - 安全
- Clear! - Clear!
喂
Hey!
（即时新闻）
（直播 拉斯维加斯陷入恐慌）
里面有人吗
Is anyone in there?
舰长 无人驾驶机拍到了新穆托的图像
Captain, our UAVs have footage of the new MUTO.
转到大屏幕上
Let's have a look.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
这是五分钟前拍到的
This is from five minutes ago.
我的天呐
My God.
全部放一遍
Playing all we have now.
近三百英尺高
It's almost 300 feet.
比另一个大多了
It's far bigger than the other one.
但这只没有翅膀
But this one doesn't have any wings.
是不同性别
A different sex?
是雌性的
A female.
它是在召唤它
That's who he's been talking to.
肯定是在求偶
It must be a mating call.
雌性保持休眠状态等待雄性成熟
The female remained dormant until the male matured.
它们在寻找放射物质
Now they're seeking radiation.
以保障繁殖
To reproduce.
综合所有数据分析 三个目标将在这里会合
Current tracking models indicate that all three targets are converging here:
旧金山海湾
San Francisco Bay.
如果把安装防护计时器的
But if we rig a nuclear warhead with a shielded timer...
核弹头安装在船上
...put it on a boat and send it...
让船距离海岸二十英里之外
...20 miles out...
用它的放射性来吸引穆托
...the radiation lures the MUTOs...
穆托会引来哥斯拉
...and the MUTOs lure Godzilla.
然后引爆核弹 这样对城市的损害最小
And we detonate, with minimal fallout risk to the city.
你在开玩笑吧 它们就吃这东西
You can't be serious. They feed on radiation.
没错 所以才用核弹当诱饵
Correct. That's why we use the bomb as bait.
爆炸会直接…
And kill them...
- 解决掉它们 - 简直是疯了
- ...with the sheer force of the blast. - This is crazy.
博士 如果你还有别的办法 我们洗耳恭听
Doctor, if you have any other ideas, I am all ears.
将军
Admiral.
博士 请讲
Yes, doctor?
哥斯拉也许就是答案
Gojira may be the answer.
我相信…
I believe.
它来这儿就是为了这个
...he's here to restore balance.
它能战胜它们
He can defeat them.
就是说 我们只能袖手旁观
And what? We just stand by and watch?
很抱歉 博士 我不能冒这个险
I'm sorry, doctor. I can't take that risk.
去准备核弹 马上运往海岸
Prep the warheads and get them moving to the coast.
- 是 长官 - 是 长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
博士 我知道你不赞成这样做
I know you don't agree with this.
但我首先考虑的是保护我们的市民
But my first priority is to safeguard our citizens.
这表停了
It's stopped.
是的
Yes.
1945年8月6号
Eight-fifteen in the morning.
上午八点十五分
August 6, 1945.
广岛
Hiroshima.
这是我父亲的
It was my father's.
都听着
Heads up.
刚接到命令 我们有了新的目的地
We've got new destination, new orders.
马上调整装备
Let's get geared up.
上士
Hey, tech sergeant.
什么情况
What's the word?
在内华达又发现了一个那种东西
Another one of those things popped up in Nevada, sir.
（加利福尼亚州 孤松镇）
好了 大家下车吧
Okay, everybody out.
只能到这儿了
Can't fly any further.
已经进入电磁脉冲的射程了
We're well in range of its EMP.
所以接下来的路程 只能靠我们的两条腿了 走吧
So from here on out, it's on the ground or it's not at all. Let's go!
好了 都听着
All right, listen up!
这列火车和这些武器将被运往旧金山
This train and these weapons are headed to San Francisco.
跟这项任务无关的人 立即下车 快
Anyone not part of this mission, disembark now!
这可不行
Negative.
我不能同意
Can't do it, sir.
这是项高风险任务 那列火车是国有资产 不是美铁公司的
This is a high-risk mission. That train is a national asset, not Amtrak.
- 能走了吗 - 准备就绪
- We good to go? - Just about.
从这些民兵洲际弹道导弹的弹壳看
From the look of the casings on those Minuteman ICBMs...
我猜数码模块被彻底忽略了 准备全面模拟改造吧
...guessing the digital module's been bypassed and you're prepping for full analog retrofit.
这样我就会让你上车
Is my jaw supposed to drop?
我知道 你是拆弹专家
I get it. You're EOD.
但我有人了 他们知道怎么做
I got my crew, they know what they're doing.
尖头对准妖怪 对吗 军士长
Aim the pointy end at the monsters, right, sarge?
你的人到底多长时间没摸过炸弹了
When was the last time you let one of your guys put their fingers in a live bomb?
听着 我是干这个的
Look, this is what I do.
这是我的工作
This is my job.
军士长
Master sergeant.
我家就在城里
My family's in the city.
所以我必须坐上那列火车
Okay? I need to get on that train.
刚才发言人已经明确表示
You heard the spokesman say...
白宫并不排除动用核武的可能性
...that the White House has not ruled out the use of nuclear force.
萨姆 你妈妈一会儿就过来
Sam, your mom's gonna be right back.
急救中心 什么事
Emergency, can I help you?
你好
Hello?
好 请稍等
Oh, yeah, just a sec.
艾丽 找你
Elle, for you.
- 等一下 马上来 - 艾丽
- Tell them I'll be there in a minute. - Elle.
是你丈夫
It's your husband.
喂
Hello?
艾丽
Elle?
福特
Ford?
上帝
Oh, God.
- 你没事吧 萨姆呢 - 我一直在到处打电话找你
- You all right? How's Sam? - I've been calling you everywhere.
- 你没事吧 - 我没事
- You okay'? - I'm fine.
- 我和萨姆在一起 - 太好了 我最担心的就是你们两个
- I've got Sam with me. - Great. Because I wanna get you both...
简直是太可怕了
Can't believe this is happening.
福特
Ford.
你没事吧
You okay? Are you doing okay?
我没事 艾丽 别担心我
I'm okay. Elle, please don't worry.
亲爱的 我好怕
Baby, I'm so scared right now.
我知道
I know.
天亮的时候我就会到医院
I'm gonna be at the hospital by sunrise.
然后把你和萨姆接出来
Then I'll get you and Sam out.
好的
Okay.
军队有办法对付这些事情
The military has a plan to deal with these things.
我会来接你们俩的
I'm coming to get you both, okay?
好的
Okay.
你能快点儿来吗
Can you please just hurry?
我会的
I Will.
艾丽
Elle?
我就是想告诉你 我爱你
I just wanted you to know that I love you.
我也爱你 你小心点儿
I love you too. Just be safe.
等着我
I'll see you soon.
中尉 快上车 出发了
Good to go! Let's move out!
受电子干扰停电的区域
As blackouts and electrical interference...
逐渐向西扩大
...radiate farther and farther west...
怪物周围两百英里范围内的 居民均受到严重影响
...citizens within 200 miles of the creature's current sphere of influence...
政府方面敦促大家尽快找到避难场所
...are being urged to please find shelter...
不要出门 不要停留在街道上
...stay indoors and stay off the roads.
911 您有什么事情
911, what's your emergency?
孩子还在车里
...kids in the car.
碎片涉及大约两英里左右
...debris going back about two miles.
女孩没有呼吸了
This girl is not breathing.
受伤的人 你必须派人来这里
... people that are hurt. Send somebody out here now!
明白
Yes, sir.
弹头已经在路上了
Yes, warheads are on the move.
我完全同意 先生
I completely agree, sir.
好了各位 开始吧
All right, people. Let's go.
我要第一时间知道穆托的确切位置
I need to know the exact location of the MUTOs ASAP.
是 长官 正在更新最新的实时数据
Aye. We're updating our models with the current tracking data now.
将军
Admiral.
什么
Yes?
请不要这么做
Please don't do this.
我知道你在担心什么 博士
I understand your concerns, doctor.
为了把这些东西
But I am sacrificing lives...
引离人口密集地区 每一分钟都有人在送命
...every minute trying to steer one of these things clear of population centers...
而现在又有两头 正在来的路上
...and now there are two more on the way.
几百万人危在旦夕 所以我希望…
There are millions of lives at risk. So all I want to know...
你能告诉我的是
...from you is:
会有用吗 杀得了它们吗
Will it work and can they be killed?
可是我们以前试过了
But we tried that before.
我们可以调整重量 百万吨级 不是千吨
We're talking dialable yield. Megatons, not kilotons.
没什么能抵挡这种威力
Nothing can withstand that blast.
五四年用来杀它的不过是小鞭炮
Makes the bomb we tried to kill it with in '54 look like a firecracker.
- 马勒斯中士 帮个忙 - 我还以为这东西…
- Sergeant Morales. Give me a hand. - I thought these nukes...
- 是遥控引爆的呢 - 穆托会干扰…
- ...all detonated by remote control. - The MUTOs knock out...
所有的电子设备
...everything electric.
包括起爆器
Including detonators.
所以没等导弹进入射程就全失灵了
Can't even get in range without these things going haywire.
但是这个
But this?
就是另一个选择
This, on the other hand, is old-school.
老式的机械计时器
Clockwork.
轻轻一按…
Takes a licking...
马上开转
...keeps on ticking.
见鬼
Holy shit.
马勒斯中士 带着无线电下来 动作快点儿 快
Sergeant Morales, get down here with that radio. On the double. Move, move!
蛇眼 亡命徒呼叫十一月
Snake Eyes, this is Bravo to November. ls the bridge...
桥梁安全吗 完毕
...clear? Over.
重复一遍
I say again:
一辆装满特需货物的火车
We got a train of VIP cargo...
驶向海岸线 桥梁安全吗 完毕
...headed for the coast. Is the bridge clear? Over.
蛇眼 收到请回答
Snake Eyes, I need a sitrep.
铁路安全吗
Are the tracks clear?
我们选择处于黄色警戒 十分钟后将进入红色警戒
We are at phase line yellow. In the next 10 mikes, we're advancing to phase line red.
是否安全 完毕
Secure or not? Over.
你觉得桥还在吗
You think it's intact?
只有一个办法能确定
Only one way to find out.
- 你负责上面 - 行
- You wanna take the top? - Sure.
你负责下面 马勒斯中士 你跟着我
You check below. Sergeant Morales, you come with me.
见鬼
Shit.
上帝
Jesus.
- 琼斯 你没事吧 - 我没事
- Jones, you all right? - Yeah, I'm good!
桥梁完好无损
The bridge is intact.
牛头犬 我是老鹰
Bulldog, this is Eagle.
可以行动 完毕
All clear to move out. Over.
收到 老鹰
Roger that, Eagle.
上车 大家上车
Let's go! Let's go, people!
请重复
Say again.
我看不见你们 在什么位置 完毕
I do not have a visual. What is your position? Over.
听不清楚 请重复 完毕
Unreadable. Say again. Over.
快卧倒
Hit the deck.
快帮我关上它
Help me turn it off, man.
跑
Run!
快跑
Move it, run!
福特
Ford! Aah!
它下水了
He's going under!
舰队 拉响碰撞警报
Boats, sound the collision alarm.
一百八十幅
Frame 180.
无法获取图像 将军
We're losing visual, admiral.
它在潜水
He's diving.
改变航向移动迅速 时速达到三十三节 而且还在提速
Changing course and moving fast. I've got him at 33 knots and picking up speed.
比我们快多了 长官
He's gonna outrun us, sir.
保持平稳
Watch the swinging!
不要晃
No swing!
喂
Hey!
等一下
Hold on!
医务兵
Medic!
都在赶往当地的公交站
They are insisting civilians make their way to the BART stations.
所有车站 都已成了临时避难所
BART stations are designated shelters.
等等 这些病人是我负责照顾的 你要带他们去哪儿
These patients are my responsibility. Where are you taking them?
带他们出城 只带重患和儿童
Across the bridges. Critical and children only.
避难所马上就满了 相信我 他们去城外会更安全
Shelters are gonna fill up fast. Trust me, they'll be safer outside the city.
- 我带着萨姆 - 不
- I can take Sam. - No, no, no.
福特马上就到
Ford's on his way.
如果你改主意 大巴十分钟后离开
If you change your mind, the buses leave in 10 minutes.
你在哪儿福特
Come on. Where are you, Ford?
这边 让他们快点儿 快点儿
This way! Keep them moving!
快点儿
Let's go. Come on, come on.
要把它弄哪儿去
Hey! Where are they taking it?
离海岸二十英里的地方 最佳聚集点
Twenty miles offshore, convergence point.
把它们引到那儿去
We're gonna lure them there.
就能一石三鸟
Three birds, one stone.
等等
Wait!
好了 萨姆
Okay, Sammy.
劳拉 感谢上帝
Laura, thank God.
萨姆 记得劳拉吧 妈妈的同事 记得吗
Sammy, you remember Laura. She's Mommy's work friend, right?
她会替妈妈照顾你一小会儿
She's gonna look after you for a little bit.
爸爸马上就来接你
Daddy's gonna be here soon.
妈妈也会很快来找你们
And I'm gonna just come get you right after.
我保证
I promise.
好吧
Okay.
好的
Okay?
来吧 宝贝儿 跟我在一起吧
Come on, sweetheart. You're gonna come with me.
妈妈要留下照顾病人
Your mom's gonna stay and help.
艾丽 我会照顾好他的
Elle, I'm gonna take care of him, okay?
- 放心 跟妈妈再见吧 - 再见 妈妈
- Say, "Bye-bye, Mommy." - Bye, Mommy.
（加利福尼亚州 奥克兰市 战术指挥部）
好了 交给我
I got him! I got him!
到这边坐下 坐下
Just sit down here.
坐下
Sit, sit.
（旧金山火警救援）
这里
Here.
你意识清醒吗
Did you lose consciousness?
我没事 真的没事
I'm okay. Really, I'm fine.
（奥克兰市海湾区公园）
报告情况 目标现在的位置
Sitrep, please. Location of targets?
雄性穆托在靠近 费拉隆群岛三十英里的地方
Male MUTO was spotted 30 miles off the Farallon Islands.
东部靠近利弗莫尔的地区有地壳震动
Showing seismic activity to the east near Livermore.
应该是雌性导致的
Should be the female closing in.
哥斯拉在哪儿
Where's Godzilla?
最后一次记录还是五小时之前的
Last contact was five hours ago.
方向零五三 深度一万英尺
Maintaining a bearing of 053 degrees, descending below a depth of 10,000 feet.
用不了一小时就能到达这里
Be here within the hour.
居民们正在想尽一切办法撤离城市
Residents are trying to get out of the city any way they can.
（西海岸市民紧急疏散）
桥上还有好几辆大巴车
There's still buses on that bridge.
来啊
Come on!
让大巴士快点儿开走
Let's get those busses through. Let's go!
（警戒线 请勿穿越）
（警察）
别把车停在这里
We're not gonna stop the buses here.
什么
What?
我听不见 孩子们…
I can't hear you. Oh, kids...
安静点儿 别吵了
...please be quiet.
移动到位 直到你能瞄准
Move into position till you have a clean line of sight!
左舷两百米处
Portside! Two hundred meters!
当心
Brace!
先别开火
Hold your fire.
见鬼
Holy shit.
该死
Oh, shit!
- 等等 - 小心
- Hold on! - Watch out!
开火
Fire! Fire! Fire!
小心
Look out!
趴在座位上 快 趴下
Get down! Get down in your seats!
让开 快让开
Please! Get down!
快让开
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
喂
Hey!
快走 快走
Move out! Move, move, move!
等等 桥上有平民 别开火
Striker! There's civilians on the bridge. Hold your fire!
快开火
Open fire!
闪开
Move! Move!
- 好了 到达目的地 - 核弹发射准备
- All right, get in there! - Prepare to arm the device!
就位
Ready! You got it?
我准备好了
I'm all set.
插入钥匙
Arming keys!
三 二 一
Three! Two! One!
到底是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
脉冲干扰
EMF .
引擎停了 失去动力
Engine's stopped! We lost power!
- 没事吧 - 没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 上面 - 开火
- Fire! - Incoming!
萨姆·布罗迪一小时前被送到了奥克兰体育场避难所
Sam Brody was checked into the Oakland Coliseum shelter an hour ago.
他很安全
He is safe.
但是没有艾丽·布罗迪的记录 应该还在城里
No record of Elle Brody. Never made it out of the city.
再查一遍 求你了 我让她等我但我没赶到
Well, check again. Please. I told her to wait for me, and I didn't make it.
很抱歉 滞留在城里的人 都被转移到地铁避难所了
They are trying to get everyone downtown into subway shelters.
你太太不会有事的
I'm sure your wife is fine.
布罗迪中尉
Lieutenant Brody!
我找布罗迪中尉
I'm looking for Lieutenant Brody.
- 你是布罗迪吗 - 是的
- Are you Brody? - Yes.
好了 都听着 雄性怪物把弹头弄到了市中心
Okay. The male delivered the warhead to the center of downtown.
意味着十万平民 会在爆炸中受到辐射
That puts 100,000 civilians in the blast radius.
但又无法远程解除
We can't stop it remotely.
模拟定时器已经安装
An analog timer has been installed.
靠近穆托五英里的范围内所有电子设备都将失灵
The MUTOs are frying electronics within a five-mile bubble.
就是说不可能从地面接近
Means approaching from ground is not an option.
只能以高跳低开的方式空降
That's why we'll be conducting a HALO insertion. Jumping altitude...
跳伞高度将在三万英尺
...Will be 30,000 feet.
滑翔到正上方实施 这儿 还有这儿
We just skate to the top and drop. Here.
如果没撞到摩天大楼 就在集结点C会合
And here. If you don't hit a skyscraper on the way, meet at rally point Charlie.
- 就在这儿 明白 - 博士 你有什么好建议吗
- Right here. Good? - Doctor, any guesses where to look?
查找地下
Underground.
如果穆托已经产卵
If the MUTOs have spawned...
它们肯定会筑巢
...they'll be building a nest.
上尉 一旦找到了弹头
Captain, when you find the warhead...
- 多久能拆除 - 长官 不知道…
- ...how long to disarm it? - Without seeing...
- 模拟定时器的模式前我无法预测 - 如果能找到它…
- ...the analog mod, I couldn't even guess. - Sixty seconds...
六十秒足够
...if I can access it.
我亲手改动过那个装置
I retrofitted that device myself.
布罗迪中尉是火车事故中
Lieutenant Brody is our only...
唯一幸存的拆弹专家
...EOD tech to survive the train attack.
看来全指望你了
Well, it sounds like we could use you.
说句不吉利的话
With all due respect...
- 如果计划失败 有备用方案吗 - 海滩的位置
- ...if that doesn't work, then what's Plan B? - The waterfront...
就在山下一公里处
...is located one klick downhill.
把它弄到码头上 装上船
Get the bomb to the pier, onto a boat...
在爆炸之前 开得离城市越远越好
...and as far away from the city as possible before it detonates.
还有问题吗
Any questions?
- 解散吧 - 就这样
- Dismissed. - That's it.
全体出发
Let's move.
中尉
Lieutenant?
可能你还不知道
They've already been briefed.
这次没有接应计划
We have no extraction plan.
如果没及时撤离 就永远留在那儿了
If you don't walk out, you don't come back at all.
我会全力以赴的
Sir, I'll do whatever it takes.
你的这个掠食者之王 博士
This alpha predator of yours, doctor...
你觉得有获胜的可能吗
...do you really think he has a chance?
人类总自以为是地认为控制了大自然
The arrogance of man is thinking nature is in our control...
恰好相反
...and not the other way around.
让它们斗吧
Let them fight.
万能的主
Oh, Lord God, we give thanks...
感谢你给予我们这样的机会
...for the opportunities you have given us...
让我们共同为国家而战
...going together as comrades to defend our great nation.
感谢你给予我们一起服役的美好时光
We thank you for the time and service that you have given us together.
我们即将奔赴战场
Now as we are about to leave one another...
请给予我们力量
...let us have the strength...
全体就位
Take position! Take position!
我看见第一小队往东去了
I saw Team 1 move to the east.
我们小队损失俩人 无线电断断续续的
Two of our team members didn't make it. I heard bits and pieces on the radio.
狙击手在屋顶已经就位
Snipers on the rooftop moving into position.
有了 找到弹头了
Here we go. Picking up the nuke.
在哪儿
Which way?
在山上一公里
One klick up the hill.
好了 找到弹头了
We found the warhead.
行动吧 在山上 这个方向 我们走
Let's go! Up the hill, this direction. Move.
喂
Hey. Hey.
看
Look.
我们走 快走
Let's move, let's move.
跟在我后面
On my six.
中士 你看看这个
Sarge, get a look at this.
继续前进 找到信号了吗
We gotta get moving. You got a signal yet?
找到了
I got it.
就在这下面
It's down there.
行动
All right, move, move!
小心点儿
Grab a line!
照亮点儿 格雷泽
More light. Grazer.
小心 当心点儿
Right, clear out.
我们走
Here we go.
当心点儿 我们走
Whoa, look out, heads up!
还剩多少时间
How much time we got left?
还有二十七分钟
We have 27 mikes.
得把它弄下来
We gotta get this thing down.
好了 我拿到了
Move, move, I got you!
当心点儿
Move it out, move it out!
Careful! Careful.
一起放 三…
And down in three...
二…
...two...
一
...one.
把盖子打开
Let's get this cover off.
好了 中尉看你的了
Lieutenant, you're up.
弄不动 封死了
It's not budging. It's sealed shut.
需要时间打开它
We need time to open it.
没时间了 快把它弄出去吧
We don't have time!
装上船运走
We gotta get it on a boat.
大家抓住弹头 一起用力
Grab the warhead! Let's move!
钻过去
Go!
抬稳了
Easy.
Easy, easy.
快 兄弟们
Move it out, guys!
中尉 快走
Lieutenant, let's go!
中尉
Lieutenant?
那是什么啊
What the hell was that?
见鬼 看见了吗
Holy shit! Did you see that?
这边
This way.
快啊 再快点
Faster, faster.
快发动引擎
Let's get this thing started.
找到引擎开关了
Find the ignition, sir?
把包给我
Give me that pack.
给你
Here you go.
拜托 快点儿
Come on, come on. Hurry.
快 快上来 快上来 快点儿
Hurry it up. Let's go, let's go!
它是奔核弹来的
She's coming for the bomb!
把核弹绑结实了
Let's get this weapon secured.
快点儿
Unh! Come on.
Come on.
（卫星定位系统）
（自动导航）
（星际旅行号）
（数千人仍然下落不明）
待在这儿别动
Stay right here.
安静
Quiet!
有声音 在这儿
I hear some people. Come on!
抓住我的手 我们来救你们了
This one's in bad shape. Come on, grab my hand. We got you.
拉他上来 拉上来
Help him up. Help him up.
新到者请注意
Attention, new arrivals:
请前往设有标记的桌子
Please proceed to the marked tables...
- 注册登记 - 请让条道
- ...for registration. - Let's make some room, please!
玛丽
Mary!
爸爸
Daddy!
萨姆
Sam.
妈妈
Mommy!
萨姆
Sammy?
妈妈
Mommy! Mommy!
我的宝贝儿
Sweetpea.
嗨
Hi!
我的宝贝儿
Hi, baby.
嗨
Hi.
亲爱的
Oh, baby.
（怪兽之王 城市救星）
[谨以此片纪念理查·福克斯以及杰克·福斯特]